DESPOINA TOUSKA

Thessaloniki, Greece

d3py.tousk@gmail.com \leq Linkedin \leq ORCID \leq Google Scolar

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Software engineer with 2+ years of experience as a research associate in the machine learning and computer vision fields. Posses abilities to identify, understand and translate program requirements into sustainable, advanced technical solutions through Python, C, C++, JavaScript, and other programs for continuous improvement of AI technologies.

EDUCATION

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Thessaloniki, Greece

MSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering

October 2013 - April 2020

- Cumulative GPA: 8.35/10
- Relevant Coursework: Pattern Recognition, Parallel & Distributed Systems, Probabilities & Statistics, Data Structures, Structured Programming, Robotics, Database Systems

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Thessaloniki, Greece March 2018 - May 2018

Collaboration for thesis completion

• Thesis: Video Forgery Detection using Autoencoder and Recurrent Neural Networks (link)

• Grade: 10/10

EXPERIENCE

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Machine Learning Engineer and Research Associate

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP)

Software Engineer and Research Intern

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Software Engineer and Research Intern

Thessaloniki, Greece September 2020 - Present

Porto, Portugal

October 2019 - February, 2020

Thessaloniki, Greece

November 2018 - September 2019

PUBLICATIONS

- D. Touska, K. Gkountakos, K. Ioannidis, T. Tsikrika, S. Vrochidis, I. Kompatsiaris. Graph-Based Data Association in Multiple Object Tracking: A Survey. MMM2023. 2023. (accepted for publication)
- Gkountakos, K., Touska, D., Ioannidis, K., Tsikrika, T., Vrochidis, S., & Kompatsiaris, I. Spatio-temporal activity detection and recognition in untrimmed surveillance videos. ICMR. 2021.
- Gkountakos, K., Galanopoulos, D., Touska, D., Ioannidis, K., Vrochidis, S., Mezaris, V., & Kompatsiaris, I. ITI-CERTH participation in ActEV and AVS Tracks of TRECVID 2021. TRECVID. 2021.
- Gkountakos, K., Galanopoulos, D., Mpakratsas, M., Touska, D., Moumtzidou, A., Ioannidis, K., ... & Kompatsiaris, I. (2020). ITI-CERTH participation in TRECVID 2020. TRECVID. 2020.
- Zampoglou, M., Markatopoulou, F., Mercier, G., Touska, D., Apostolidis, E., Papadopoulos, S., ... & Kompatsiaris, I. Detecting tampered videos with multimedia forensics and deep learning. MMM2019, 2019

SKILLS

Languages: English (fluent, C2, IELTS: 7.5/9), Greek (native), German (beginner, A2).

Programming Languages: Python (advanced), C/C++ (intermediate), JavaScript (intermediate), HTML (intermediate), CSS (intermediate), SQL (beginner).

Libraries: PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, TensorFlow.js, NumPy, Pandas, Sci-Kit Learn.

Production tools: Docker, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Git